Finding Aid for Marcia Barrabee Papers, 1961-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Marcia Barrabee Papers 1961-1969
Barrabee, Peter
2 linear feet
857 Aa 2
Ann Arbor peace activist during the Vietnam War era; correspondence and other materials relating to her activities within peace organizations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Marcia Barrabee (donor no. 5820 ) and came to the library in 1976. Periodic additions have been made.
The collection is open to research.
Marcia Barrabee was a peace activist during the Vietnam War era. She was also newsletter editor of Ann Arbor Women for Peace.
The collection includes correspondence, newsletters, printed material, and newspaper clippings concerning the Women Strike for Peace, the House Un-American Activities Committee, the National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, disarmament, the draft, civil defense and fallout shelters. The collection has been arranged into the following series: Ann Arbor Women for Peace; Women Strike for Peace; Peace Issues; and Surveillance Files.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor Women for Peace.; Civil defense.; Disarmament.; Draft.; Student Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam.; Pacifism.; Peace--Societies, etc.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Women Strike for Peace.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
- Ann Arbor Women for Peace
  - Undated, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1969 (Box 1)
- Women Strike for Peace
  - General, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the House Un-American Activities Committee subpoenas issued to the Women Strike for Peace 1962-1963, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning attempts to abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee, 1964-1968. (Box 1)
  - Women Strike for Peace National Information Memo
    - 1962 (Box 1)
    - Jan-December 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
  - Women Strike for Peace Memo
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - January-December 1965, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Women's Peace Movement Bulletin
    - January-December 1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - January-December 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
- Peace Issues
  - Peace Inquiry and Action Weekly (Box 2)
  - Addresses, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Disarmament, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Draft, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Arms industry conversion (Box 2)
  - Peaceful alternatives, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Dow Chemical Company protest 1968, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Teach-in on the draft at The University of Michigan 1968 (Box 2)
  - National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam 1967, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Step Toward Peace Day 1963 (Box 2)
  - Civil defense and fallout shelters, 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Notebooks on peace activities, 7 volumes (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    (include Ann Arbor Strike for Peace phone chain)
  - Vietnam Summer 1967 (Box 2)
    (financial records, etc.)
- Surveillance
  - File kept by Michigan State Police (Box 2)
  - File kept by FBI (Box 2)